<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/tags/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Justin Nguyen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justinnuwin.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lawrence Livermore National Lab</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2020/</guid><description>I originally interned at LLNL over the summer of 2017 (click hear to learn more about my group), and joined part-time during university to support the software side of the project longer-term. To facilitate me working at the national lab part-time during university I am contracted under J&amp;amp;A Film Preservation, a company that has been working with the Film Scanning and Re-Analysis Project for several years. I am continuing to develop vision algorithms for scientific measurements, but I am also working on streamlining our team&amp;rsquo;s workflow by using the latest workflow automation tools like Dagster.</description><content>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2017">I originally interned at LLNL over the summer of 2017 (click hear to learn more about my group)&lt;/a>, and joined part-time during university to support the software side of the project longer-term.
To facilitate me working at the national lab part-time during university I am contracted under J&amp;amp;A Film Preservation, a company that has been working with the Film Scanning and Re-Analysis Project for several years.
I am continuing to develop vision algorithms for scientific measurements, but I am also working on streamlining our team&amp;rsquo;s workflow by using the latest workflow automation tools like Dagster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past 2 years working for the Film Scanning and Re-analysis project I have added several new measurement tools to our measurement tool written in Python.
These tools include &lt;strong>global-segmented&lt;/strong> film exposure measurement methods, and a a new fireball detection pipeline that I architected utilizing spectral analysis and temporal edge tracking.
I also added measurement statistics for all of the data our group generates using scikit-learn to better understand our measurements.
In addition, I have refactored our codebase to explicitly support both CLI and GUI (Tk) methods to run which will allow the team to programmatically re-analyze and update old results more easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the refactoring sprint, I was able to abstract our application logic to work well on both desktop environments for developing new codes and on HPC environments provided by Livermore Computing&amp;rsquo;s supercomputers.
Dagster, a workflow orchestration tool, ties our workflow together with its pipeline and asset management systems, and I developed a multithreaded image loader as a CPython module to further speed up our program&amp;rsquo;s analysis.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>