<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenCV on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/tags/opencv/</link><description>Recent content in OpenCV on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Justin Nguyen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justinnuwin.com/tags/opencv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lawrence Livermore National Lab</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2020/</guid><description>This is where I currently work. I started as an intern at LLNL, click here to learn more about what I did then (and still do now)
In the meantime some of the things I have done so far are:
Manage data collection, storage, and visualization for the Film Scanning and Re-Analysis Project Architect object detection pipeline utilizing spectral analysis, temporal edge tracking, and exposure analysis of images Develop image processing GUI tools utilizing TK using Python and OpenCV Implement statistical methods to automatically check measurement data for quality Building data-driven image processing models to further automate accurate film measurements Stay tuned for updates!</description></item><item><title>Cal Poly Autonomous Vehicle Security Group</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/cpavsec-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/cpavsec-2020/</guid><description>The Cal Poly Autonomous Vehicle Security Group is headed by Dr. Bruce DeBruhl who is involved in security research for autonomous vehicles, IOT devices, and all things networked. The projects I have worked on in this group have been primarily focused towards the security of platoons of autonomous vehicles. Vehicle platoons require extensive communication to stay cohesive and ensure that no collisions occur. The two paradigms that vehicles communicate are vehicle-to-vehicle (V2V) using a protocol like DSRC or vehicle-to-infrastructure (V2I) usually using cellular infrastructure like 4G-LTE and 5G.</description></item><item><title>Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/experience/llnl-2017/</guid><description>During my first summer at Cal Poly, I interned at the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL) working on the Film Scanning and Re-Analysis Project headed by nuclear physicist Gregory Spriggs. The goal of the project is to digitize all the nuclear test films before they decay and reanalyze the results, as many of the results from the 1940s through the early 1960s were plagued with guesswork from the manual measurement process.</description></item></channel></rss>