<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepages on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/</link><description>Recent content in Homepages on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Justin Nguyen</copyright><atom:link href="https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/about/</guid><description>Hi there! My name is Justin and I am currently a masters student at Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) in the Electrical and Computer Engineering Program (ECE). My interests are focused in embedded systems and machine learning. I am working on several proejcts relating to edge-ML: how we can apply computationally intensive algorithms on resource-constrained embedded and mobile platforms. I am really passionate about collaborating with others to build amazing things, so browse my projects and feel free to reach out!</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/contact/</guid><description>Feel free to reach out to me via these platforms:
Github Linkedin Twitter</description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/education/</guid><description>Carnegie Mellon University M.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering • May 2020 - May 2021
Low Power code for IOT: Theory behind designing software (especially RTOS) to take advantage of &amp;ldquo;dark silicon&amp;rdquo; on embedded hardware to minimize energy use, thereby maximizing battery life. Speech Recognition and Understanding: Study how speech recognition systems model human speech using HMM+GMM, HMM+DNN, and end-to-end models. Implement simple HMM+GMM word recognizer and Listen, Attend, Spell (LAS) speech recognizer.</description></item><item><title>Skills</title><link>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/skills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justinnuwin.com/homepage/skills/</guid><description>Python and packages such as Numpy, Pandas, PyTorch, Keras, and Sklearn C/C++ for desktop and embedded applications with experience with libraries such as OpenCV, Boost, gRPC, ProtoBuf Proficient with machine learning techniques and libraries. Experience working with computer vision and speech recognition Hardware design PCB layout in Allegro and Altium Experience with embedded systems, particularly: ultra-low power systems, interconnect protocols, network protocols, and RF design View all my projects and experiences by tag to find something more specific.</description></item></channel></rss>