<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>machine learning on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</title><link>https://justinnuwin.com/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in machine learning on Justin Nguyen / Software Engineer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020 Justin Nguyen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://justinnuwin.com/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Evaluation of ASR in Musical Environments</title><link>https://justinnuwin.com/projects/asr-music-semester-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://justinnuwin.com/projects/asr-music-semester-project/</guid><description>Github
ASR is used heavily in eyes-busy or hands-busy situations and often time the user may be speaking over noise. My peers and I are particularly interested in how music effects ASR decoding. We use several music datasets of varied genre or broken-down instrumentation to allow us to perform in-depth anaysis of how different aspects of music influences speech recognizer&amp;rsquo;s performance. We then train a new model from what we have learned to see if we could improve the original model&amp;rsquo;s performance.</description></item><item><title>Denoising EEG Signals</title><link>https://justinnuwin.com/projects/denoising-eeg-semester-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://justinnuwin.com/projects/denoising-eeg-semester-project/</guid><description>Github
EEGs are extremely interesting to the signal processing world as the signals from them are high dimensional and localized spatially, spectrally, and temporally. These signals are extremely low amplitude and artifacts appear in the measured signal due to normal human processes like blinking, breathing, and moving; or noise can appear due to the external factors such as line noise or sound in the room. My peers and I implement Viola&amp;rsquo;s ICA CorrMap procedure to denoise EEGs, but rather than retreiving EEG artifacts in-situ, we use Cho&amp;rsquo;s EEG dataset which separately records subjects in both rest states and performing various &amp;lsquo;noisy&amp;rsquo; actions prior to a motor imagery trial.</description></item><item><title>Cal Poly Autonomous Vehicle Security Group</title><link>https://justinnuwin.com/experience/cpavsec-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://justinnuwin.com/experience/cpavsec-2020/</guid><description>The Cal Poly Autonomous Vehicle Security Group is headed by Dr. Bruce DeBruhl who is involved in security research for autonomous vehicles, IOT devices, and all things networked. The projects I have worked on in this group have been primarily focused towards the security of platoons of autonomous vehicles. Vehicle platoons require extensive communication to stay cohesive and ensure that no collisions occur. The two paradigms that vehicles communicate are vehicle-to-vehicle (V2V) using a protocol like DSRC or vehicle-to-infrastructure (V2I) usually using cellular infrastructure like 4G-LTE and 5G.</description></item></channel></rss>